Finding Aid for the Philipp Rezek Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Philipp Rezek Papers
1938-1941
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0363
.07 linear_feet
Scope and Contents
This collection contains personal letter written by friends and family of Philipp Rezek, who were Jewish refugees. The collection covers Austria’s takeover by the Germans in 1938, the family’s departure, internment camps, arrival to the United States, and medical school. A few of the letters are written from right to left to pass German censors.
The majority of this collection is in German.
- Correspondence
  - Scrapbook, 1940s
  - January 11, 1939
  - May 4, 1939
  - July 5, 1939
  - July, 1939
  - July 27, 1939
  - August 14, 1939
  - August 18, 1939
  - September 24, 1939
  - September 29, 1939
  - October 3, 1939
  - October 26, 1939
  - November 2, 1939
  - November 28, 1939
  - December 11, 1939
- Correspondence
  - January 2, 1940
  - January 21, 1940
  - January 24, 1940
  - April 12, 1940
  - May 8, 1940
- Correspondence
  - March 4, 1941
  - March 8, 1941
  - April, 1941
  - April 22, 1941
  - April 23, 1941
  - April 28, 1941
  - May 13, 1941
  - w/newspaper clipping, May 20, 1941
  - June 16, 1941
  - June 21, 1941
  - July 4, 1941
  - July 13, 1941
  - August 14, 1941
  - August 20, 1941
  - August 25, 1941
  - September 4, 1941
  - September 5, 1941
  - September 14, 1941
  - September 16, 1941
  - September 16, 1941
  - September 23, 1941
  - October 14, 1941
  - October 19, 1941
  - November 7, 1941
  - November 20, 1941
  - December 15, 1941
  - December 18, 1941
- Correspondence - Postcards
  - December 19, 1939
  - January 18, 1940
  - October 27, 1941
- Manuscripts
  - ‘What Really Happened on, March 13, 1938’
  - ‘Three Years’
- News Release
  - July 15, 1938
  - January, 1940